Alexandru Gutu

Address: Seifertova 4, Prague 3-Žižkov

Phone: +420608138648

E-mail: alexgutuacces@yahoo.com

Skype: gutu_alexandru1

Linkedin: https://se.linkedin.com/in/alexandru-gutu-98b6028b

Driver's license: B



Working Skills Complete knowledge of TCP/IP.

6 months Windows Server 2012 and 3 months of Ubuntu administration. One-year experience of troubleshoot ip-camera network connection in LAN, WLAN, WAN, MAN.

Testing IP-camera network functionality, security and documenting results. One-year of practical knowledge to read error logs, server-reports, user-reported errors of IP-cameras on window, Liunux and on cloud-systems.

Escalation of services to specific product specialists.

Understand how to design and implement computer networks in LAN,

WAN, MAN.

Understand QoS (all services) in WAN.

Good conduct of Firewall troubleshooting tools, IDS, tracert, ping, Strong academic knowledge of Troubleshoot DNS multicast, NAT, VPN.

Comprehensive knowledge of Bash scripting.

Good communication with local and international contingent of workers.

Employment

Sep 2019 - current Multifunctional website-specialist and programmer

Hicleaning, Prague

Responsible for keeping advertisement up for cleaning business. Supporting services of our website. Troubleshooting, and fixing issues. Adding/removing services. Managing emails and controlling workflow. Documenting the

income. Booking orders.

June 2018 – Sep 2019 Dispatcher - support specialist

Jarotrans, Prague

Send orders to drivers, provide instructions and make sure it is carried out. I instruct driver upon what routes to drive and ensure the client cargo is

delivered at appointed time and destination.

Making calculation of km-s and total calculation for invoicing customers.

Jan 2017 – Nov 2017 Technical Support Engineer

Axis Communication, Lund

Provide guidance to customers through web portal, chat and phone. Troubleshoot and solve issue involving Axis products such as network cameras, video encoders, video net-recorders, audio systems, doorstations, VMS, video analytics and cloud-based services. Giving support for configuration and installation of video systems. Solving issues of IP-camera system(s) connected in LAN, WAN, WLAN networks by use of software tools, LAB and Database search engine. Analysing IP-camera server reports. Escalating of service issues to product manager or product specialist.

Dec 2015 – Nov 2017 Network technician assistant

Folkuniversitetet, Halmstad, Sweden

Administrating LAN network. Troubleshooting and reconfiguring VPN on

HP Switch and IP-phones. Install windows and Linux on computer.

FTP-Server implementation between two business-office-sites. Firewall and Proxy Server configuration.

Education

Jan 2013 – Dec 2015 Master's program of Computer Network Engineering.

Halmstad University, Sweden

Simulation of Complex Computer Networks, Modern Communication

Systems, CCNA, CCNP Routing and Switching.

Project: Remote Secured Access to the Home Server. Technology: DTLS, MTLS, IPsec, HTTPS and VPN, SLA service-level-agreement, Two-factor

authentication.

Sep 2014 – Dec 2015 Network Design and Computer Management.

Halmstad University, Sweden

Windows System Administration, Linux System Administration, Computer

Networks, CCNA Security, CCNP Routing and Switching, Wireless Communication, Advanced Computer Network Troubleshooting.

Certification Axis Network Video (2017)

CCNP Troubleshooting (cisco certified network professional)

Language English fluent

Russian native Romanian native Swedish very good Czech intermediate French intermediate

Programming CSS, HTML, Java script,

Operation Systems Windows 7, 10, Server 2012, MAC OS, Linux/UNIX

Software & programs Cisco IOS, VMware, Snoop, Wireshark, IDS, tracert, Combo fix, Null scan/ X-

mas tree, Office Suite, cloud-based software as part of Office 365, Visio,

Outlook, One note, Apple-Bonjour

Communication skills Work in team. Build technical skills. Solution oriented. Progress oriented.

Innovations prone. Find solution for best customer experience.

Interests Football, volleyball, drawing, music.

References Florian Combacau- Technical services manager, Axis Communications

Tel +46 272 1974 Email: florian.combacau@axis.com

Maxim Burobin – General Manager of Logistics – Jarotrans,

Tel +420 778 778 779

Andrey Kravets- director of Hicleaning, Prague

Tel +420 777 901 810

More info can be provided at the request